A Guide to the Mark Kac papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA170
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Reprints, Papers, Lectures, and Correspondence Files, Accession 2006:064, 1934-1986; 9; 11.83 Cubic Feet 9 record storage boxes.
  - Moerbeke, V., Some Probabilitistic Aspects of Scattering Theory, Claredon Press, 87-96, 1974 April-1975 (Box 4)
  - Luttinger, Scattering Length and Capacity, Ann. Inst. Fourier, 25, 317-321, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Thompson, J. C., Correlation Functions in the Spherical and Mean Spherical Models, J. Math. Phys., 18, 1650-1650, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Fox, R., A Remark on the Theory of Fluctuations Far from THermodynamic Equilibrium, BuiSystems, 8, 187-191, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Semiclassical Quantum Mechanics and Morse's Theory, Trends in Applications of Pure Maths. to Mechs. Vol. II (Pitman), 1978 (Box 4)
  - On the Asympt. No. of Bound States for Ctn. Attractive Potentials, (Krein) Topics Functl. Anal., Advs. Math. Supp. 3, 159-167, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Nonlinear Dynamics and Inverse Problems, Procds., Intl. Su. Schl. Sta. Mech. IV, FUndl. Probl. Sta. Sta. Mech. IV, ARS Polona, 1978 (Box 4)
  - (Logan, J.), Fluctuations, Stud. In Statl. Mechanics, VII, 1-60, 1979 (Box 4)
  - (Benguria) Quantum Langevin Equation, Phys. Rev. Let., 46/1, 1-4, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Some Mathl. Probls. Suggd. By Quests. In Phys. I. Asymptotic Degeneracy and Long Range Order, II, Langevin E. and Approach to Equilibrium, Lectures at AMS Colloquium, San Francisco, 1981 January 7-10 (Box 4)
  - How I Became a Mathematician, Sent to "Rehovot," Weiz. Inst., 1981 April 13 (Box 4)
  - Non-Markovian Diffusion in Idealized Lorentz Gases, Arch. Ratl. Mechanics and Analysis, 51, 106-135, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Mainly Quantum Langevin Equation (Box 5)
  - Many Important Notes, etc., Including Benguria's Notes on Our Brownian Motion Paper (Box 5)
  - Biography/Bibliography (Box 5)
  - Bibliography (Box 5)
  - Battelle Colloquium on Critical Phenomena, Geneva, 1970 September (Box 5)
  - Notebook, 1977 May (Box 5)
  - Notebook, 1972 April 28 (Box 5)
  - Notebook, 1979 January (Box 5)
  - Donsker's Inequality (Box 5)
  - Engimas of Chance, Final Manuscript (Box 5)
  - Engimas of Chance, Galleys (Box 5)
  - Discrete Thoughts: Essays on Mathematics, Science and Philosophy (Box 5)
  - Some Probabilistic Aspects of the Boltzmann Equation, Acta Physica Austriaca, Suppl. X, 379-400, 1973 (Box 5)
  - On Some Isospectral Second Order Differential Operators, Proc. NAS. 71, 2350-2351, 1974 (Box 5)
  - A Stochastic Model Related to the Telegrapher's Equation, Rocky Mountain Journal of Mathematics, 4, 497-509, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Intro-Bio, Prologue (Box 5)
  - On an Explicit Soluble System of Non-linear Differential Equations Relatied to Ctn. Toda Lattices, Ad. Maths., 16, 1975 (Box 5)
  - (Ziff, Uhlenbeck), The Ideal Bose-Einstein Gas, Revisited, Physics Reports. 32C/4, 170-48, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Birkhoff Prize Talk, Mathl. Intelligencer, 1/2, 1978 (Box 5)
  - A Mathematician Looks at Medicine, The American Journal of Medicine, 66, 725-726, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Probabilistic Methods in Some Problems of Scattering Theory, Rocky Mountain Journal of Mathematics, 4, 511-537, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Chapter I (Box 5)
  - Chapter II (Box 5)
  - Chapter III (Box 5)
  - Chapter IV (Box 5)
  - Chapter V (Box 5)
  - Chapter VI (Box 5)
  - Chapter VII (Box 5)
  - Postscript (Box 5)
  - Manuscript (Box 5)
  - "On the Eigen-values of Certain Hermitian Forms," by Mark Mac, W. L. Murdock and G. Szego, Reprint, 1953 (Box 6)
  - "On Eigen-values of Certain Hermitian Forms," Corrections (Box 6)
  - "On Deviations Between Theoretical and Empirical Distributions," Reprint, 1949 (Box 6)
  - "Ramanujan Sums and Almost Periodic Functions," by P. Erods, Mark Kac, E. R. van Kampen and A. Wintner, Reprint, 1940 (Box 6)
  - "Remark on the Preceding Paper by A. Refnyi", 1955 (Box 6)
  - Kac, Mark, Reprints from Rockefeller University (RU) #78 (Box 6)
  - "The Spherical Model of a Ferrimagnet," by T. H. Berlin and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1952 (Box 6)
  - "Partial Sums of Independent Random Variables," by Mark Kac and H. Pollard, Reprint, 1950 (Box 6)
  - "On Tests of Normality and Other Tests of Goodness of FIt Based on Distance Methods,' by Mark Kac, J. Kiefer and J. Wolfowitz, Reprint, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Physics Today, 1964 October (Box 6)
  - "Proceedings of the Third Berkeley Symposium on Mathematical Statistics and Probability," Reprint, 1955 (Box 6)
  - "A Sampling Method for Determining the Lowest Eigenvalue and the Principal Eigenfunction of Schrodinger's Equation," by M. D. Donsker and Mark Kac, 1950 (Box 6)
  - "The Spherical Model of a Ferromagnet,' by T. H. Berlin and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1952 (Box 6)
  - "On Tests of Normality and Other Tests of Goodness of FIt Based on Distance Methods," Reprint, 1955 (Box 6)
  - "Distribution of Eigenvalues of Certain Integral Operators", 1956 (Box 6)
  - "Some Remarks on the Use of Probability in Classiccal Statistical Mechanics", 1956 (Box 6)
  - "On a Theorem of Zygmund," Reprint, 1951 (Box 6)
  - "A Remark on Wiener's Tauberian Theorem," Reprint, 1965 (Box 6)
  - "Probability Theory: Its Role and Its Impact," Reprint, 1962 (Box 6)
  - "Scattering Length and Capacity," by Mark Kac and J. M. Luttinger, Reprint, 1975 (Box 6)
  - "The Making of Statisticians," Ed. by J. Gani, Reprint, 1982 (Box 6)
  - "The Probabilistic Methods in Ome Problems of Scattering Theory," The Rocky Mountain Journal of Mathematics, Reprint, 1974 (Box 6)
  - "One Dimensional Gas in Gravity," Reprint, 1969 (Box 6)
  - "Phase Transition and Eigenvalue Degeneracy of a One Dimensional Anharmonic Oscillator," by Colin J. Thompson and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1969 (Box 6)
  - "On Some Probabilistic Aspects of Classical Analysis," Reprint, 1970 (Box 6)
  - "The Role of Models in Understanding Phase Transitions," Reprint (Box 6)
  - "The Spherical Model and the Infinite Spin Demensionality Limit," Reprint, 1971 (Box 6)
  - "On Applying Mathematics: Reflections and Examples," Reprint, 1972 (Box 6)
  - "Possible Origin of the Quantized Vortices in He II," by S. J. Putterman, Mark Kac and G. E. Uhlenbeck, 1972 (Box 6)
  - "Methodes Probabilistes Dans La Theorie du Potentiel", 1956 (Box 6)
  - "On Occupation Time for Markoff Processes," by D. A. Darling and Mark Kac (Box 6)
  - "A Class of Limit Theorems," Reprint, 1957 (Box 6)
  - "Probability in Classical Physics" (Box 6)
  - "Uniform Distribution on a Sphere," Reprint, 1957 (Box 6)
  - "Some Remarks on Stable Proecesses," Reprint (Box 6)
  - "Some Remarks on Stable Processes with Independent Increments," Reprint (Box 6)
  - "Toeplitz Forms and Their Applications," by U. Grenander and G. Szego, Review by Mark Kac, Reprint, 1958 (Box 6)
  - "Remark on Recurrence TImes," Reprint, 1959 (Box 6)
  - "On Rapidly Mixing Transformations and an Application to Continued Fractions," Reprint, 1958 (Box 6)
  - "Large Excursions of Gaussian Processes," Reprint, 1959 (Box 6)
  - "Some Remarks on Osillators Driven by a Random Force," Reprint, 1979 (Box 6)
  - "On the Partition Function of a One-Dimensional Gas," Reprint, 1959 (Box 6)
  - "The Emergence of Statistical Thought in Exact Sciences," in The Heritage of Copernicus, Ed. by Jerzy Neyman, 1974 (Box 6)
  - "On Some Periodic Toda Lattices," Reprint, 1975 (Box 6)
  - "On an Explicitly Soluble System if on Linear Differential Equations Related to Certain Toda Lattices," Reprint, 1975 (Box 6)
  - "Teorie Statystyczne W Cialach Stalych Cieczach I Gazach", 1974 (Box 6)
  - "Phenomenes Stochastiques et Theorie des Fluctuations", 1974 (Box 6)
  - "An Example of 'Counting WIthout Counting'," Reprint, 1975 (Box 6)
  - "A Complete Solution of the Periodic Toda Problem", 1975 (Box 6)
  - "The Social Responsibility of the Academic Community," Reprint (Box 6)
  - "Some Reflections of a Mathematician on the Nature and the Role of Statistics," Reprint, 1975 (Box 6)
  - "On Some Modified Spherical Models," Reprint, 1975 (Box 6)
  - "Fluctuations and the Boltzmann Equation. I.," by Jonothan Logan and Mark Kac, 1976 (Box 6)
  - "Henri Lebesgue I polska szkila matematyczna: obserwacje I wspomnienia," Reprint, 1978 (Box 6)
  - "Henri Lebesgue et L'Ecole Mathematique Polonaise: Apercu et Souvenirs", 1975 (Box 6)
  - "Some Probabilistic Aspects of Scattering Theory" (Box 6)
  - Scattering Length and Capacity," Reprint, 1975 (Box 6)
  - "Correlation Functions in the Spherical and Mean Spherical Models," Reprint, 1977 (Box 6)
  - "Fluctuations Near and Far from Equilibrium" (Box 6)
  - "Distribution Problems in the Theory of Random Noise," in Proceedings of Symposia in Applied Mathematics, Volume II, Reprint, 1950 (Box 6)
  - "Partial Sums of Independent Random Variables," Reprint, 1950 (Box 6)
  - "Corrections to the Paper 'Remarks on Fluctuations of Sums of Independent Randon Variables'," by K. L Chung and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1953 (Box 6)
  - "On Some Corrections Between Probability Theory and Differential and Integral Equations," Reprint, 1951 (Box 6)
  - "A Sampling Method for Determining the Lowest Eigenvalue and the Principal Eigenfunction of Schrodinger's Equation," by M. D. Donsker and Mark Kac, 1950 (Box 6)
  - "The Spherical Model of Ferromagnet," by T. H. Berlin and Mark Kac, 1952 (Box 6)
  - "A Combinatorial Solution of the Two-Dimensional Ising Model", 1952 (Box 6)
  - "An Application of Probability Theory to the Study of Laplace's Equation," Reprint (Box 6)
  - "Signal and Noise Problems," Reprint, 1954 (Box 6)
  - "Toeplitz Matrices, Translation Kernels and a Related Problem in Probability Theory" (Box 6)
  - "Some Combinatorial Aspects of the Theory of Toeplitz Matrices," Reprint, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Statistical Mechanics of Assemblies of Couples Oscillators," by G. W. Ford, Mark Kac, and P. Mazur, Reprint, 1965 (Box 6)
  - "A Remark on Wiener's Tauberian Theorem," Reprint, 1965 (Box 6)
  - "Can Liberal Arts Colleges Abandon Science?", 1966 (Box 6)
  - "On the Mathematical Mechanism of Phase Transition," Reprint, 1966 (Box 6)
  - "Can One Hear the Shape of a Drum?" Repint, 1966 (Box 6)
  - "A Mathematical View of the Theory of Phase Changes," from Perspectves in Modern Physics:M Essays in Honor of Hans A. Bethe, Reprint, 1966 (Box 6)
  - "Some Mathematical Problems in the Theory of Phase Transitions," Reprint, 1967 (Box 6)
  - "Towards a Unified View on Mathematical Theories of Phase Transitions," Reprint, 1968 (Box 6)
  - "A Matter of Opinion," in Scientific Research, 1968 March (Box 6)
  - "Problem of the Disordered Chain," by Ta-Feng Lin, 1970 (Box 6)
  - "On Certain Toeplitz-like Matrices and Their Relation to the Problem of Lattice Vibrations," Reprint, 1968 (Box 6)
  - "Some Analytic Aspects of Probabilistic Potential Theory," by Z. Ciesielski and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1969 (Box 6)
  - "Asymptotic Behavior of a CLass of Determinants," Reprint, 1969 (Box 6)
  - "Critical Behavior of Several Lattice Models with Long-Range Interaction", 1969 (Box 6)
  - "Some Mathematical Models in Science", 1969 (Box 6)
  - "Stochastic Differential Equations-VII: The Physical Background of Langevin's Equation" (Box 6)
  - "Possible Origin of the Quantized Vortices in He II," by S. J. Putterman, Mark Kac and G. E. Uhlenbeck, Reprint, 1972 (Box 6)
  - "Probability Theory: Its Role and Its Impact," Reprint, 1962 (Box 6)
  - "Chance and Regularity" (Box 6)
  - "Some Mathematical Problems Suggesested by Questions in Physics," Reprint, 1981 (Box 6)
  - "Semiclassical Quantum Mechcanics and Morse's Theory," Reprint (Box 6)
  - "Weiner and Integration in Function Speces," Reprint, 1966 (Box 6)
  - "Nonlinear Dynamics and Inverse Problems" (Box 6)
  - The Rocky Mountain Journal of Mathematics, Volume 4, Number 3, 1974 Summer (Box 6)
  - "A Stochastic Model Related to the Telegrapher's Equation," in The Rocky Mountain Journal of Mathematics, Reprint, 1974 (Box 6)
  - "Some Probabilistic Aspects eprintof the Boltzmann Equation," Reprint, 1973 (Box 6)
  - "A Remark on the Theory of Fluctuation Fra from Thermodynamic Equilibrium," by Ronald F. Fox and Mark Kac, 1977 (Box 6)
  - "The Ideal Bose-Einstein Gas, Revisited," iin Physics Reports, by R. M. Ziff, G. E. Uhlenbeck and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1977 (Box 7)
  - "On Some Mathematical Models Exhibiting Phase Transitions and On What Might Be Learned From Them" (Box 7)
  - "Semicalssical Quatnum Mechanics and Morse's Theory," Reprint (Box 7)
  - The Mathematical Intelligencer, 1978 (Box 7)
  - "The Search for the Meaning of Independence" (Box 7)
  - "Mathematics" (Box 7)
  - "A Formula for the Pressure in Statstical Mehanics," Reprint, 1973 (Box 7)
  - "A Discrete Version of the Inverse Scattering Problem," by K. M. Case and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1973 (Box 7)
  - "Non-Markovian Diffusion in Idealized Lorentz Gases," by D, J. Gates, I. Gerst, and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1973 (Box 7)
  - "Some Probabilistic Aspects of the Boltzmann Equation," Reprint, 1973 (Box 7)
  - "Mathematics and Computer Science," Review of Mark Kac: Probability, Number Theory, and Statistical Physics, by K. Baclawski and M. D. Donsker, 1980 (Box 7)
  - "Bose-Eisntein Condensation in the Presence of Impurities," Reprint, 1973 (Box 7)
  - "Will Computers Replace Humans?" (Box 7)
  - "Lectures on Mathematical Aspects of Phase Transitions," from Studies in Mathematical Physics, Reprint, 1970 (Box 7)
  - "Phase Transitions," Reprint, 1973 (Box 7)
  - "Bose-Einstein Condensation in the Prsence of Impurities. II," Reprint, 1974 (Box 7)
  - The American Mathematical Monthly, 1974 June-July (Box 7)
  - "On Some Isospectral Second Order Differential Operators," Reprint (Box 7)
  - Except of Proceedings of the Sixth Berkeley Symposium on Mathematical Statitics and Prbability, Reprint, 1970 (Box 7)
  - "Study of Several Lattice Systems with Long-Range Forces," Reprint, 1963 (Box 7)
  - "Probability Theory as a Mathematical Discipline and as a Tool in Engineering and Science," Reprint, 1963 (Box 7)
  - "On the van der Waals Theory of Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. I. Discussion of a One-Dimensional Model", 1963 (Box 7)
  - "On the van der Waals Theory of Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. II. Discussion of the Distribution Functions", 1963 (Box 7)
  - "On the van der Waals Theory of Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. III. Discussion of the Critical Region", 1964 (Box 7)
  - "Probability," in Scientific American, Reprint, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "A Trigonometrical Series" (Box 7)
  - "Une remarque sur les series trigonometriques" (Box 7)
  - "Sur les functions independantes (I)" (Box 7)
  - "Sur les functions independantes (III)" (Box 7)
  - "Sur les functions independantes (IV)" (Box 7)
  - "Sur les functions independantes (V)", 1937 (Box 7)
  - "Une remarque sur les polynomes de M. S. Bernstein", 1937 (Box 7)
  - "Une remarque sur les equations functionnelles" (Box 7)
  - "Quelques Remarques sur les Zeros des integrales de Fourier", 1938 (Box 7)
  - "Sur les Fonctions 2nt-(2nt)-1/2" (Box 7)
  - "On a Charaterization of the Normal Distribution" (Box 7)
  - "Circular Equidistrubutions and Statistical Independence", 1939 (Box 7)
  - "On Buffon's Problem and its Generalizations", 1939 (Box 7)
  - Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society, 1940 (Box 7)
  - "Ramanujan Sums and Almost Period Funcions," by P. Er5ods, Mark Kac, E. R. van Kampen, ans A. Wintner, Reprint, 1940 (Box 7)
  - "Almost Periodicity and the Representation of Integers as Sums of Squares" (Box 7)
  - "The Gaussian Law of Errors in the Theory of Additive Number Theoretic Functions," by P. Erdos and Mark Kac (Box 7)
  - "Translated Functions and Statistical Independence," by R. P. Agnew and Mark Kac (Box 7)
  - "Convergence and DIvergence of Non-Harmonic Gap Series", 1941 (Box 7)
  - Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society, 1941 (Box 7)
  - "Two-Number Theoretic Remarks" (Box 7)
  - "Note on Patiral Sums of the Exponential Series", 1942 (Box 7)
  - "On the Distribution of Values of Trigonometric Sums with Linearly Independent Frequencies" (Box 7)
  - "Convergene of Certain Gap Series", 1943 (Box 7)
  - "Statistical Analysis of Certain Types of Random Functions," by H. Hurwitz, Jr. and Mark Kac, Repint, 1944 (Box 7)
  - "Random Walk in the Presence of Abosrbing Barriers," Reprint, 1945 (Box 7)
  - "Inequalities for Fourier Transforms of Postive Functions," by R. P. Boas, Jr. and Mark Kac, 1945 (Box 7)
  - "A Remark on Independence of Linear and Quadratic Forms Involving Independent Gaussian Variables", 1945 (Box 7)
  - "On the Distribution of Values of the Type (SIgma) (2kt)", 1946 (Box 7)
  - "On Certain Limit Theorems of the Theory of Probability," by P. Erdos and Mark Kac, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Transactions of the American Mathematical Society, Volume 59, 1946 January-June (Box 7)
  - "On the Theory of Noise in Radio Receivers with Square Law Detectors," Reprint, 1947 (Box 7)
  - "On the Number of Positive Sums of Independent Random Variables," by P. Erdos and Mark Kac, 1947 (Box 7)
  - "Random Walk and the Theory of Brownian Motion," in The American Mathematical Monthly, 1947 (Box 7)
  - "An Explicit Representation of a Stationary Gaussian Process" (Box 7)
  - "A Gap Theorem," Reprint, 1948 (Box 7)
  - "On the Charateristic Functions of the Distributions of Estimates of Various Deviations in Samples from a Normal Populations," Reprint, 1948 (Box 7)
  - "On Distributions of Certain Wiener Functionals," Reprint, 1949 (Box 7)
  - "On Deviations Between Theoretical and Empirical Distributions," Reprint, 1949 (Box 7)
  - "On the Average Number of Real Roots of a Random Algebraic Equation (II)," in the Proceedings of the London Mathematical Society, Volume 50, 1949 (Box 7)
  - "Probability Methods in Some Problems of Analysis and Number Theory", 1949 (Box 7)
  - "Mathematics: Its Trends and Its Tensions," in Occasional Papers of The Rockefller Institute, Reprint, 1961 (Box 7)
  - "Matematyka jej kierunki I napiecia," Reprint, 1963 (Box 7)
  - "Analysis of a Basic Queuing Problem Arising in Computer Systems," by P. E. Boudreau and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1961 (Box 7)
  - "A Note on Learning Signal Detection," Reprint, 1962 (Box 7)
  - "A Discrete Problem with Variable Service Times," by P. E. Boudreau, J. S. Griffin, Jr., and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1962 (Box 7)
  - "An Elementary Queuing Problem," by P. E. Boudreau, J. S. Griffin, Jr., and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1962 (Box 7)
  - "Two Number-Theoretic Remarks" (Box 7)
  - "Large Excursions of Gaussian Processes," Reprint, 1959 (Box 7)
  - "Matematyka, jej kierunki I napiecia," Reprint, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Trinity College Presents A Science Symposium to Honor The Trinity College Associates, Program, 1961 March 18 (Box 7)
  - "Mathematics: Trends and Tensions," in the Boston University Journal (Box 7)
  - "Probability Theory: Its Roles and Its Impact," Reprint, 1962 (Box 7)
  - "Mathematics: Its Trends and Its Tensions," from the Occasional Papers of The Rockefelelr Institute, Reprints, 1961 (Box 7)
  - "On the van der Waals THeory of the Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. II. Discussion of the Distribution Functions," by G. E. Uhlenbeck, P. C. Hemmer and Mark Kac, 1963 (Box 7)
  - "Study of Several Lattice Systems with Long-Range Forces," Reprint, 1963 (Box 7)
  - "Chance and Reguarity", 1962 (Box 7)
  - Physics Today, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "The Work of T. H. Berlin in Statistical Mechanics...a Personal Reminiscence," Reprint, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "Probability," in Scientific American, Reprint, 1964 September (Box 7)
  - Kac, Mark, Probabiity, #94- (64-0218), Negatives, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "A Gap Theorem," Reprint, 1948 (Box 7)
  - "On the Mathematical Mechanism of Phase Transition," Reprint, 1966 (Box 7)
  - "On the Charateristic Functions of the Distribution of Esitmates of Various Deviations in Samples from a Normal Populaton," Reprint, 1948 (Box 7)
  - "Marginalia: Statistical Odds and Ends," Reprint, 1948 (Box 7)
  - American Scientist, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Letter of Recommendation, A (Box 7)
  - Letter of Recommendation, B (Box 7)
  - Letter of Recommendation, C (Box 7)
  - Letter of Recommendation, D (Box 7)
  - Letter of Recommendation, E (Box 7)
  - Letter of Recommendation, F (Box 7)
  - Letter of Recommendation, G (Box 7)
  - Letter of Recommendation, H (Box 7)
  - Letter of Recommendation, J-K (Box 8)
  - Letter of Recommendation, L (Box 8)
  - Letter of Recommendation, M (Box 8)
  - Letter of Recommendation, N (Box 8)
  - Letter of Recommendation, O-P (Box 8)
  - Letter of Recommendation, R (Box 8)
  - Letter of Recommendation, Sa-Sh (Box 8)
  - Letter of Recommendation, Si-Su (Box 8)
  - Letter of Recommendation, T (Box 8)
  - Letter of Recommendation, U-Z (Box 8)
  - Ozawa, Shin, Reprints and Offprints (Box 8)
  - "The National Cancer Chemotherapy Program," by Emil Frei III, 1982 (Box 8)
  - "Cancer Chemotherapy," by John Cairns and Peter Boyle, 1982 (Box 8)
  - The Causes of Cancer, by Richard Doll and Richard Peto, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Notebook (Box 8)
  - Notebook, Lectures Notes, 1963 February (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 8)
  - Dugundji, J. (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - "On an Eleboration of Mark Kac's Theorem Concerning Eigenvalues of -(triangle) in a Region with randomly Distributed Small Obstacles," by Shin Ozawa, Reprint, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Repsonse by Mark Kac (Box 8)
  - "A Mathematical Look at Medicine," Reprint, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Letters (Box 8)
  - "Study of Several Lattice Systems with Long-Range Forces," Reprint, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Mickiewicz Dziady, Adam, cz. III, Ustep, Przeglad Wojska/Fragment (Box 8)
  - Committee of Concerned Scientists (Box 8)
  - Notebook (Box 8)
  - "Dehydrated Elephants' Revisited" (Box 8)
  - For Your Information (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (in Polish) (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Workshop, "A Response to the Challenge of Emerging Synthese in Science", 1984 (Box 8)
  - Kac, Michael (Box 8)
  - "Mathematic: Reflections on the Present and Thoughts About the Future" (Box 8)
  - Kac, Mark (Box 8)
  - Untitled (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 8)
  - "Some Reflections of a Mathamatican on teh Nature and the Role of Statistics," Reprint, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence and Copy of Manuscript from Daniel K. Kevles, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with Nico from Riijksuniversiteit Utrecht, Instituut voor theoretische fysica, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with Seymour Martin Lipset, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Theoretical Physics Department at Columbia University (Box 8)
  - Burke, John A, Jr., Dean of the Division of Sciences, Mathematics and Engineering, Trinity Univserity, San Antonio, Texas (Box 8)
  - Deborah 8092 (Box 8)
  - Steinhaus (Box 8)
  - Summer Institute on Spectral Theory and Statistical Mechanics, 1965, ed. by J. D. Pincus, From the Applied Mathematics Department-Brookhaven National Laboratory (Box 8)
  - American Scientist (Box 9)
  - Correspondence Regarding to Mark Kac Publications (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 9)
  - "Marceli Stark in Memoriam," by Mark Kac (Box 9)
  - "Correction to the Mean Field Critical Temperature for Kac Interactions," by Jean Briemont and Jean-Raymond Fontaine (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - "Second Quantization in a Nutshell," Notes (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, Harper and Row Publishers (Box 9)
  - Correspondence with Jensen, and Linda Peterson (Box 9)
  - University Business,Cornell (Box 9)
  - Kac, Mark, Photographs (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Articles, and Certificates (Box 9)
  - Dartmouth College, Dedicatory Conference, 1961 November 3 (Box 9)
  - Los Alamos (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 9)
  - Memorabilia (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Award Programs, and Newspaper Clippings (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Reprints and Photocopies of Mathematics Notes and Equations (Box 9)
  - "Will Computers Replace Humans?" THe Greatest Adventure, Rockefeller University Press, 1974 (Box 9)
  - "Some Combinatorial Aspects of the Theory of Toeplitz Matrices," Proc. IBM Sc. Comp. Symp., 1964 (Box 9)